<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<scenario>
  <scenarioData id="9">
    <title>Family-Farm Carter</title>
    <titleDe>Familienbetrieb Huber</titleDe>
    <description>Joe Carter is an enthusiastic farmer in the USA and works together with his wife Mary and his brother John on his medium sized farm.</description>
    <descriptionDe>Joe Huber ist leidenschaftlicher Landwirt und arbeitet gemeinsam mit seiner Frau Maria und seinem Bruder John auf einem mittelgroßen Betrieb.</descriptionDe>
    <roleplayScenario>Joe/Johann Carter, Mary Carter (Wife) and John Carter (Brother) are managing a large farm. 
Joe is a workaholic farmer, responsible for the farm and doing most of the work. Mary and John are helping on the fields but are not professional farmers.</roleplayScenario>
    <playerCharacterName>Joe Carter</playerCharacterName>
    <playerCharacterNameDe>Joe Huber</playerCharacterNameDe>
    <status>published</status>
    <mapConfigurationId>3</mapConfigurationId>
    <mapName>Riverbend Springs</mapName>
    <mapConfigName/>
    <mapGameId>MapUS</mapGameId>
    <createdAt>2025-12-31 14:34:08</createdAt>
    <updatedAt>2026-05-14 21:58:34</updatedAt>
  </scenarioData>
  <neighbours>
    <neighbour id="21" name="Brian Winter" nameDe="Brian Winter" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Known" role="Neighbour" job="Farmer" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="2" bottom="3" bottomColorIndex="9" face="5" faceColorIndex="1" top="6" topColorIndex="5" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="2" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="5" footwear="2" footwearColorIndex="3" hairStyle="1" hairStyleColorIndex="17" beard="24" beardColorIndex="17">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Stressed</item>
        <item>Professional</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Brian is a comparatively young farm owner who has taken over the family business and is attempting to reorient it using modern methods and technologies. His focus lies on efficiency, animal health, and data-driven management—strategies that lead him to rely heavily on sensor technology, digital systems, and optimized workflows.

In his day-to-day life, Brian often appears tense, as he is tasked with simultaneously maintaining the stability of the business and undertaking its comprehensive modernization. This transition entails organizational pressure, financial strain, and—quite frequently—resistance from those around him or from his own family. Consequently, he often has little patience for delays or traditional working methods.

In his interactions with neighbors and business partners, he maintains a professional and businesslike demeanor. He communicates clearly, expects reliability, and prefers direct arrangements without unnecessary detours. Ambiguous or inefficient working methods frustrate him quickly—a reaction that occasionally makes him appear distant or impatient.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Brian ist ein vergleichsweise junger Tierhalter, der den Familienbetrieb übernommen hat und versucht, ihn mit modernen Methoden und Technologien neu auszurichten. Sein Fokus liegt auf Effizienz, Tiergesundheit und datenbasierter Betriebsführung, wodurch er stark auf Sensorik, digitale Systeme und optimierte Abläufe setzt.

Im Alltag wirkt Brian häufig angespannt, da er gleichzeitig den Betrieb stabil halten und umfassend modernisieren muss. Die Umstellung bringt organisatorischen Druck, finanzielle Belastung und nicht selten auch Widerstand aus dem Umfeld oder der Familie mit sich. Diese Situation führt dazu, dass er oft wenig Geduld für Verzögerungen oder traditionelle Arbeitsweisen hat.

Im Umgang mit Nachbarn und Geschäftspartnern tritt er professionell und sachlich auf. Er kommuniziert klar, erwartet Verlässlichkeit und bevorzugt direkte Absprachen ohne lange Umwege. Unklare oder ineffiziente Arbeitsweisen frustrieren ihn schnell, was ihn gelegentlich distanziert oder ungeduldig wirken lässt.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="90" vehicleId="60" name="FLIEGL ASW 271" manufacturer="FLIEGL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fliegl/asw271/asw271.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer"/>
      <vehicle id="83" vehicleId="11" name="AGROMASZ POV 5 XL" manufacturer="AGROMASZ" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/agromasz/pov5xl/pov5xl.xml" type="attachment" category="Plow"/>
      <vehicle id="82" vehicleId="1236" name="JOHNDEERE PickUp 1150" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/pickup1150/pickup1150.xml" type="attachment" category="Weight"/>
      <vehicle id="78" vehicleId="712" name="BERGMANN TSW 6240 W" manufacturer="BERGMANN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/bergmann/tsw6240w/tsw6240w.xml" type="attachment" category="Manure Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="77" vehicleId="682" name="VAEDERSTAD Carrier XL 625" manufacturer="VAEDERSTAD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/vaderstad/carrierxl625/carrierxl625.xml" type="attachment" category="Disc Harrow"/>
      <vehicle id="67" vehicleId="95" name="KUHN PROLANDER 7500" manufacturer="KUHN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kuhn/prolander7500/prolander7500.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="66" vehicleId="72" name="JOHNDEERE RDF35" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/headerrd35f/headerrd35f.xml" type="attachment" category="Header / Cutter"/>
      <vehicle id="65" vehicleId="82" name="JOHNDEERE S7" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/seriess7/seriess7.xml" type="combine"/>
      <vehicle id="64" vehicleId="390" name="FLIEGL PFW 18000 MaxxLine Plus" manufacturer="FLIEGL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fliegl/pfw18000maxxlineplus/pfw18000maxxlineplus.xml" type="attachment" category="Slurry Tank"/>
      <vehicle id="63" vehicleId="336" name="AMAZONE UX 5201 Super" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/ux5201super/ux5201super.xml" type="attachment" category="Sprayer"/>
      <vehicle id="48" vehicleId="6" colorIndex="4" name="SKODA Enyaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/enyaq/enyaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.2" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
      <vehicle id="42" vehicleId="18" name="BEDNAR OMEGA OO 6000 FL" manufacturer="BEDNAR" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/bednar/omega6000fl/omega6000fl.xml" type="attachment" category="Seeder"/>
      <vehicle id="39" vehicleId="76" name="JOHNDEERE 8R" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/series8r/series8r.xml" type="tractor large"/>
      <vehicle id="38" vehicleId="74" name="JOHNDEERE 6R (230-250)" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/series6r/series6rextralarge.xml" type="tractor"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="20" name="Emma Kensington" nameDe="Emma Hansen" age="31-50" gender="female" relationship="Known" role="Neighbour" job="Farmer" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="2" bottom="19" bottomColorIndex="1" face="1" faceColorIndex="1" top="28" topColorIndex="12" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="1" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="10" footwear="2" footwearColorIndex="1" hairStyle="13" hairStyleColorIndex="11" beard="63" beardColorIndex="11">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Friendly</item>
        <item>Supportive</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Together with her husband, Emma runs a diversified agricultural operation specializing in the cultivation of vegetables and grains. A portion of their harvest is sold directly at local markets, while larger quantities are marketed through wholesalers and regional buyers. Their farm is well-organized and strongly focused on efficiency and quality.

In her interactions with neighbors and business partners, Emma is open, friendly, and helpful. She is regarded as someone who communicates in a straightforward manner and prefers finding solutions together rather than endlessly debating problems. She is particularly well-connected within the regional agricultural sector, where she maintains stable and fair relationships.

Her supportive nature is especially evident during stressful periods, such as planting or harvest seasons. Whenever possible, she lends a hand to other farms—or accepts help herself—without hesitation. She places great value on mutual support within the farming community and views collaboration as an essential part of her daily life.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Emma betreibt gemeinsam mit ihrem Ehemann einen vielseitigen landwirtschaftlichen Betrieb, der sich auf Gemüse- und Getreideanbau spezialisiert hat. Ein Teil der Ernte wird direkt auf lokalen Märkten verkauft, während größere Mengen über Großhändler und regionale Abnehmer vermarktet werden. Ihr Betrieb ist gut organisiert und stark auf Effizienz und Qualität ausgerichtet.

Im Umgang mit Nachbarn und Geschäftspartnern ist Emma offen, freundlich und hilfsbereit. Sie gilt als jemand, der unkompliziert kommuniziert und gerne gemeinsam Lösungen findet, statt Probleme lange auszudiskutieren. Besonders in der regionalen Landwirtschaft ist sie gut vernetzt und pflegt stabile, faire Beziehungen.

Ihre unterstützende Art zeigt sich vor allem in stressigen Zeiten wie Aussaat oder Ernte. Wenn es möglich ist, hilft sie anderen Betrieben aus oder nimmt selbst Hilfe an, ohne lange zu zögern. Sie legt Wert auf gegenseitige Unterstützung innerhalb der landwirtschaftlichen Gemeinschaft und sieht Zusammenarbeit als wichtigen Bestandteil ihres Alltags.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="92" vehicleId="58" name="FENDT 900 Vario" manufacturer="FENDT" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fendt/vario900/vario900.xml" type="tractor large"/>
      <vehicle id="84" vehicleId="11" name="AGROMASZ POV 5 XL" manufacturer="AGROMASZ" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/agromasz/pov5xl/pov5xl.xml" type="attachment" category="Plow"/>
      <vehicle id="81" vehicleId="1131" name="AGCO 1500" manufacturer="AGCO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/agco/weight1500/weight1500.xml" type="attachment" category="Weight"/>
      <vehicle id="76" vehicleId="390" name="FLIEGL PFW 18000 MaxxLine Plus" manufacturer="FLIEGL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fliegl/pfw18000maxxlineplus/pfw18000maxxlineplus.xml" type="attachment" category="Slurry Tank"/>
      <vehicle id="75" vehicleId="680" name="UNIA ARES XL" manufacturer="UNIA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/unia/aresxl/aresxl.xml" type="attachment" category="Disc Harrow"/>
      <vehicle id="62" vehicleId="50" name="FENDT FreeFlow 25FT" manufacturer="FENDT" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fendt/freeflow25ft/freeflow25ft.xml" type="attachment" category="Header / Cutter"/>
      <vehicle id="61" vehicleId="52" name="FENDT 5275 C SL" manufacturer="FENDT" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fendt/series5275csl/series5275csl.xml" type="combine"/>
      <vehicle id="60" vehicleId="393" name="HARDI AEON 5200 DELTA FORCE" manufacturer="HARDI" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/hardi/aeon5200/aeon5200.xml" type="attachment" category="Sprayer"/>
      <vehicle id="59" vehicleId="338" name="AMAZONE ZG-TS 10001" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/zgts10001/zgts10001.xml" type="attachment" category="Fertilizer Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="47" vehicleId="104" colorIndex="5" name="LIZARD Pickup 2017" manufacturer="LIZARD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lizard/pickup2017/pickup2017.xml" type="car"/>
      <vehicle id="37" vehicleId="7" name="KRAMPE Big Body 750 S" manufacturer="KRAMPE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krampe/bigBodyS750/bigBodyS750.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer"/>
      <vehicle id="36" vehicleId="94" name="KUHN ESPRO 6000 RC" manufacturer="KUHN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kuhn/espro6000rc/espro6000rc.xml" type="attachment" category="Seeder"/>
      <vehicle id="35" vehicleId="12" name="AMAZONE Cenio 4000 Super" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/cenio4000/cenio4000.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="33" vehicleId="57" name="FENDT 700 Vario" manufacturer="FENDT" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fendt/vario700/vario700.xml" type="tractor"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="19" name="Jacob Miller" nameDe="Jakob Müller" age="50-99" gender="male" relationship="Friend" role="Neighbour" job="Farmer" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="3" onepieceColorIndex="2" bottom="0" bottomColorIndex="5" face="2" faceColorIndex="1" top="0" topColorIndex="10" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="1" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="10" footwear="4" footwearColorIndex="1" hairStyle="15" hairStyleColorIndex="19" beard="63" beardColorIndex="19">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Cautious</item>
        <item>Neutral</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Jacob is an experienced third-generation dairy farmer who runs a medium-sized family farm, which he manages jointly with his two sons. The farm has grown over many years and is firmly rooted in traditional structures, which he has evolved through careful adjustments to meet modern demands.

In his interactions with others, Jacob appears calm, composed, and rather reserved. He listens before speaking and rarely makes decisions on the spur of the moment. Particularly in business matters or dealings with neighbors, he takes care to avoid unnecessary risks and to steer clear of conflicts whenever possible.

His cautious nature is most evident when it comes to investments, new technologies, or major changes to farm operations. He favors proven methods and scrutinizes innovations thoroughly before integrating them into the business. This approach has enabled him to manage the farm with stability—even if, as a result, he is sometimes perceived as being too slow or conservative.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Jakob ist ein erfahrener Milchviehhalter in dritter Generation und führt einen mittelgroßen Familienbetrieb, den er gemeinsam mit seinen zwei Söhnen bewirtschaftet. Der Hof ist über viele Jahre gewachsen und basiert stark auf traditionellen Strukturen, die er mit vorsichtigen Anpassungen an moderne Anforderungen weiterentwickelt hat.

Im Umgang mit anderen wirkt Jakob ruhig, kontrolliert und eher zurückhaltend. Er hört erst zu, bevor er sich äußert, und trifft Entscheidungen selten spontan. Besonders in geschäftlichen oder nachbarschaftlichen Fragen achtet er darauf, keine unnötigen Risiken einzugehen und Konflikte möglichst zu vermeiden.

Seine vorsichtige Art zeigt sich vor allem bei Investitionen, neuen Technologien oder größeren Veränderungen im Betriebsablauf. Er bevorzugt bewährte Methoden und prüft Neuerungen sehr genau, bevor er sie in den Betrieb integriert. Diese Haltung hat ihm geholfen, den Hof stabil zu führen, auch wenn er dadurch manchmal als zu langsam oder konservativ wahrgenommen wird.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="91" vehicleId="142" name="VALTRA S" manufacturer="VALTRA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/valtra/sseries/sseries.xml" type="tractor large"/>
      <vehicle id="85" vehicleId="11" name="AGROMASZ POV 5 XL" manufacturer="AGROMASZ" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/agromasz/pov5xl/pov5xl.xml" type="attachment" category="Plow"/>
      <vehicle id="80" vehicleId="1183" name="CLAAS W 1800" manufacturer="CLAAS" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/claas/w1800/w1800.xml" type="attachment" category="Weight"/>
      <vehicle id="74" vehicleId="680" name="UNIA ARES XL" manufacturer="UNIA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/unia/aresxl/aresxl.xml" type="attachment" category="Disc Harrow"/>
      <vehicle id="73" vehicleId="715" name="BRANTNER TA 12050 Power Spread +" manufacturer="BRANTNER" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/brantner/ta12050/ta12050.xml" type="attachment" category="Manure Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="70" vehicleId="139" name="UNIA FENIX 3000/3" manufacturer="UNIA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/unia/fenix3000/fenix3000.xml" type="attachment" category="Seeder"/>
      <vehicle id="58" vehicleId="41" name="CLAAS VARIO 620" manufacturer="CLAAS" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/claas/vario620/vario620.xml" type="attachment" category="Header / Cutter"/>
      <vehicle id="57" vehicleId="38" name="CLAAS EVION 450" manufacturer="CLAAS" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/claas/evion450/evion450.xml" type="combine"/>
      <vehicle id="56" vehicleId="345" name="BERTHOUD Vantage 4300" manufacturer="BERTHOUD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/berthoud/vantage4300/vantage4300.xml" type="attachment" category="Sprayer"/>
      <vehicle id="55" vehicleId="337" name="AMAZONE ZA-TS 3200" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/zats3200/zats3200.xml" type="attachment" category="Fertilizer Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="54" vehicleId="131" name="RUDOLPH DK 280 RP" manufacturer="RUDOLPH" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/rudolphsohn/dk280rp/dk280rp.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer"/>
      <vehicle id="46" vehicleId="141" name="VAEDERSTAD TopDown 600" manufacturer="VAEDERSTAD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/vaderstad/topdown600/topdown600.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="45" vehicleId="12" name="AMAZONE Cenio 4000 Super" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/cenio4000/cenio4000.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="44" vehicleId="34" name="CLAAS ARION 470-410" manufacturer="CLAAS" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/claas/arion400/arion400.xml" type="tractor"/>
      <vehicle id="43" vehicleId="5" colorIndex="8" name="SKODA Kodiaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/kodiaq/kodiaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.3" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="18" name="Marcus Brown" nameDe="Markus Braun" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Friend" role="Neighbour" job="Farmer" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="0" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="0" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="0" bottom="1" bottomColorIndex="0" face="1" faceColorIndex="0" top="62" topColorIndex="0" gloves="13" glovesColorIndex="0" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="0" footwear="1" footwearColorIndex="0" hairStyle="2" hairStyleColorIndex="3" beard="0" beardColorIndex="0">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Stressed</item>
        <item>Uncooperative</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Marcus is a local farmer who has managed a relatively small, highly traditional farm for many years. Most of his farm equipment is old; he repairs and continues to use it for as long as possible—a practice that increasingly complicates and slows down his daily work routine.

In his day-to-day interactions, Marcus often appears tense and somewhat unapproachable. The constant pressure stemming from equipment repairs, the time required for his work, and the ever-rising demands of modern farming have left him feeling weary and irritable over the years. He frequently regards new methods or modern technology with skepticism, having had negative experiences with past investments or operational changes.

He is not always cooperative in his dealings with neighbors and fellow farmers. Reaching agreements can be difficult, as he is quick to feel pressured or tends to resist changes to established procedures. His conflicts arise less from personal animosity and more from a sense of being overwhelmed—from the feeling that he is losing control of the situation.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Markus ist ein regionaler Landwirt, der seit vielen Jahren einen eher kleinen, stark traditionell geführten Betrieb bewirtschaftet. Seine landwirtschaftlichen Geräte sind größtenteils alt und werden so lange wie möglich repariert und weitergenutzt, was den Arbeitsalltag zunehmend erschwert und verlangsamt.

Im täglichen Umgang wirkt Markus häufig angespannt und wenig zugänglich. Der ständige Druck durch Reparaturen, Zeitaufwand und steigende Anforderungen in der Landwirtschaft hat ihn über die Jahre müde und reizbar gemacht. Neue Methoden oder moderne Technik begegnet er oft mit Skepsis, da er schlechte Erfahrungen mit Investitionen oder Umstellungen gemacht hat.

Im Kontakt mit Nachbarn und anderen Landwirten ist er nicht immer kooperativ. Absprachen können schwierig sein, da er sich schnell unter Druck gesetzt fühlt oder Veränderungen im Ablauf ablehnt. Konflikte entstehen bei ihm weniger aus persönlicher Ablehnung, sondern eher aus Überforderung und dem Gefühl, den Überblick zu verlieren.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="128" vehicleId="680" name="UNIA ARES XL" manufacturer="UNIA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/unia/aresxl/aresxl.xml" type="attachment" category="Disc Harrow"/>
      <vehicle id="93" vehicleId="22" name="BRANTNER Z 18051/2 XXL Power Flex" manufacturer="BRANTNER" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/brantner/z18051/z18051.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer"/>
      <vehicle id="86" vehicleId="98" name="LEMKEN Juwel 6 M V" manufacturer="LEMKEN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lemken/juwel6/juwel6.xml" type="attachment" category="Plow"/>
      <vehicle id="79" vehicleId="1131" name="AGCO 1500" manufacturer="AGCO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/agco/weight1500/weight1500.xml" type="attachment" category="Weight"/>
      <vehicle id="72" vehicleId="378" name="FARMTECH Supercis 800" manufacturer="FARMTECH" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/farmtech/supercis800/supercis800.xml" type="attachment" category="Slurry Tank"/>
      <vehicle id="53" vehicleId="109" name="MASSEYFERGUSON MF 8570 %s" manufacturer="MASSEYFERGUSON" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/masseyferguson/mf8570header/mf8570header.xml" type="attachment" category="Header / Cutter"/>
      <vehicle id="52" vehicleId="108" name="MASSEYFERGUSON MF 8570" manufacturer="MASSEYFERGUSON" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/masseyferguson/mf8570/mf8570.xml" type="combine"/>
      <vehicle id="50" vehicleId="394" name="HARDI MEGA 1200L" manufacturer="HARDI" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/hardi/mega1200l/mega1200l.xml" type="attachment" category="Sprayer"/>
      <vehicle id="49" vehicleId="337" name="AMAZONE ZA-TS 3200" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/zats3200/zats3200.xml" type="attachment" category="Fertilizer Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="31" vehicleId="33" name="CHALLENGER MT600 Series" manufacturer="CHALLENGER" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/challenger/mt655/mt655.xml" type="tractor large"/>
      <vehicle id="30" vehicleId="61" name="GREATPLAINS SOLID STAND 1500" manufacturer="GREATPLAINS" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/greatplains/seeder1500/seeder1500.xml" type="attachment" category="Seeder"/>
      <vehicle id="29" vehicleId="67" colorIndex="1" name="INTERNATIONAL Series 200" manufacturer="INTERNATIONAL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/international/series200/series200.xml" type="car"/>
      <vehicle id="28" vehicleId="85" name="KNOCHE ECO-CULTIVATOR 300" manufacturer="KNOCHE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/knoche/ecocultivator300/ecocultivator300.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="27" vehicleId="59" name="FIAT 160-90 DT" manufacturer="FIAT" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fiat/series90/series90.xml" type="tractor"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="17" name="Paul Meyer" nameDe="Paul Meier" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Known" role="Business Partner" job="Agricultural Contractor" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="7" onepieceColorIndex="7" bottom="0" bottomColorIndex="5" face="2" faceColorIndex="1" top="0" topColorIndex="10" gloves="2" glovesColorIndex="2" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="1" footwearColorIndex="2" hairStyle="5" hairStyleColorIndex="19" beard="2" beardColorIndex="19">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Uncooperative</item>
        <item>Stressed</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Paul runs an agricultural contracting business, offering services such as harvesting, manure spreading, tillage, and other fieldwork to local farms. His operation is heavily dependent on time constraints, weather conditions, and seasonal peak periods—factors that often make his daily routine hectic and highly demanding in terms of planning.

In his interactions with clients, Paul often comes across as curt and lacking in patience. He is focused squarely on completing jobs quickly and ensuring the efficient utilization of his machinery. He typically rejects lengthy discussions or last-minute changes to the workflow, as these place an additional strain on his already tight schedule.

Due to his heavy workload and constant pressure to meet deadlines, he frequently appears stressed and tense. Particularly during the harvest season or during periods of critical weather, he can seem uncooperative if operations do not proceed exactly according to plan. In such instances, his concern is less about personal conflicts and more about the absolute necessity of keeping his business running smoothly.

Despite his gruff demeanor, Paul is highly competent and experienced in all aspects of fieldwork. Provided that agreements are established clearly and well in advance, he works reliably and efficiently. However, he expects the same level of clarity and commitment from his business partners.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Paul betreibt ein landwirtschaftliches Lohnunternehmen und bietet Dienstleistungen wie Erntearbeiten, Gülleausbringung, Bodenbearbeitung und weitere Feldarbeiten für regionale Betriebe an. Sein Betrieb ist stark von Zeitdruck, Wetterbedingungen und saisonalen Spitzen abhängig, was seinen Alltag häufig hektisch und planungsintensiv macht.

Im Umgang mit Kunden wirkt Paul oft kurz angebunden und wenig geduldig. Er ist darauf fokussiert, Aufträge schnell abzuarbeiten und Maschinen effizient auszulasten. Lange Diskussionen oder kurzfristige Änderungen im Ablauf lehnt er meist ab, da sie seinen ohnehin engen Zeitplan zusätzlich belasten.

Durch die hohe Arbeitslast und den ständigen Termindruck wirkt er häufig gestresst und angespannt. Besonders in der Erntezeit oder bei wetterkritischen Phasen kann er unkooperativ erscheinen, wenn Abläufe nicht exakt nach Plan laufen. Dabei geht es ihm weniger um persönliche Konflikte, sondern um die Notwendigkeit, den Betrieb am Laufen zu halten.

Trotz seiner ruppigen Art ist Paul fachlich sehr kompetent und erfahren in allen Bereichen der Feldarbeit. Wenn Absprachen klar und frühzeitig getroffen werden, arbeitet er zuverlässig und effizient. Er erwartet jedoch dasselbe Maß an Klarheit und Verbindlichkeit von seinen Geschäftspartnern.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="125" vehicleId="1236" name="JOHNDEERE PickUp 1150" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/pickup1150/pickup1150.xml" type="attachment" category="Weight"/>
      <vehicle id="124" vehicleId="1909" name="OXBO BP2140e" manufacturer="OXBO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/oxbo/bp2140e/bp2140e.xml" type="greenbeanharvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="123" vehicleId="1910" name="OXBO EPD540e" manufacturer="OXBO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/oxbo/epd540e/epd540e.xml" type="peaharvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="122" vehicleId="1911" name="OXBO MKB-4TR" manufacturer="OXBO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/oxbo/mkb4tr/mkb4tr.xml" type="spinachharvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="121" vehicleId="1734" name="DEWULF GBC" manufacturer="DEWULF" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/dewulf/gbc/gbc.xml" type="attachment" category="vegetableHarvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="120" vehicleId="1966" name="KVERNELAND Miniair Nova 6m" manufacturer="KVERNELAND" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kverneland/miniairnova6m/miniairnova6m.xml" type="attachment" category=""/>
      <vehicle id="119" vehicleId="1919" name="ROPA KEILER 2 RK22" manufacturer="ROPA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/ropa/keiler2/keiler2.xml" type="attachment" category="potatoHarvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="118" vehicleId="1768" name="GRIMME GL 420" manufacturer="GRIMME" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/grimme/gl420/gl420.xml" type="attachment" category="potatoPlanting"/>
      <vehicle id="117" vehicleId="1920" name="ROPA Maus 5" manufacturer="ROPA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/ropa/maus5/maus5.xml" type="beetloading"/>
      <vehicle id="116" vehicleId="1921" name="ROPA RR-XL 9x45" manufacturer="ROPA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/ropa/rrxl9/rrxl9.xml" type="attachment" category="beetHarvesterCutters"/>
      <vehicle id="115" vehicleId="1923" name="ROPA Tiger 6S" manufacturer="ROPA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/ropa/tiger6s/tiger6s.xml" type="beetharvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="114" vehicleId="1846" name="KRONE VariPack V 190 XC Plus" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/varipackv190xc/varipackv190xc.xml" type="attachment" category="balersRound"/>
      <vehicle id="113" vehicleId="1841" name="KRONE BiG Pack 1290 HDP VC" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/bigpack1290hdpvc/bigpack1290hdpvc.xml" type="attachment" category="balersSquare"/>
      <vehicle id="112" vehicleId="1930" name="SAMASZ KDD 941 STH" manufacturer="SAMASZ" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/samasz/kdd941sth/kdd941sth.xml" type="attachment" category="mowers"/>
      <vehicle id="111" vehicleId="1931" name="SAMASZ KDF 341 S" manufacturer="SAMASZ" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/samasz/kdf341s/kdf341s.xml" type="attachment" category="mowers"/>
      <vehicle id="110" vehicleId="1844" name="KRONE EasyFlow 300 S" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/easyflow300s/easyflow300s.xml" type="attachment" category="forageHarvesterCutters"/>
      <vehicle id="109" vehicleId="1843" name="KRONE X-Collect 900-3" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/collect900_3/collect900_3.xml" type="attachment" category="forageHarvesterCutters"/>
      <vehicle id="108" vehicleId="1842" name="KRONE BiG X 1180" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/bigx1180/bigx1180.xml" type="forageharvesters"/>
      <vehicle id="107" vehicleId="854" name="NEWHOLLAND 980CR 18-30" manufacturer="NEWHOLLAND" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/newholland/cr980_1830/cr980_1830.xml" type="attachment" category="Corn Header"/>
      <vehicle id="106" vehicleId="117" name="NEWHOLLAND FD250 FlexDraper®" manufacturer="NEWHOLLAND" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/newholland/fd250/fd250.xml" type="attachment" category="Header / Cutter"/>
      <vehicle id="105" vehicleId="115" name="NEWHOLLAND CR11" manufacturer="NEWHOLLAND" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/newholland/cr11/cr11.xml" type="combine"/>
      <vehicle id="104" vehicleId="390" name="FLIEGL PFW 18000 MaxxLine Plus" manufacturer="FLIEGL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/fliegl/pfw18000maxxlineplus/pfw18000maxxlineplus.xml" type="attachment" category="Slurry Tank"/>
      <vehicle id="103" vehicleId="338" name="AMAZONE ZG-TS 10001" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/zgts10001/zgts10001.xml" type="attachment" category="Fertilizer Spreader"/>
      <vehicle id="102" vehicleId="336" name="AMAZONE UX 5201 Super" manufacturer="AMAZONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/amazone/ux5201super/ux5201super.xml" type="attachment" category="Sprayer"/>
      <vehicle id="101" vehicleId="821" name="KUHN MAXIMA 3 TI L" manufacturer="KUHN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kuhn/maxima3til/maxima3til.xml" type="attachment" category="Planter"/>
      <vehicle id="100" vehicleId="62" name="HORSCH Avatar 12.25 SD" manufacturer="HORSCH" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/horsch/avatar1225/avatar1225.xml" type="attachment" category="Seeder"/>
      <vehicle id="99" vehicleId="682" name="VAEDERSTAD Carrier XL 625" manufacturer="VAEDERSTAD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/vaderstad/carrierxl625/carrierxl625.xml" type="attachment" category="Disc Harrow"/>
      <vehicle id="98" vehicleId="95" name="KUHN PROLANDER 7500" manufacturer="KUHN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kuhn/prolander7500/prolander7500.xml" type="attachment" category="Cultivator"/>
      <vehicle id="97" vehicleId="102" name="LEMKEN Titan 18" manufacturer="LEMKEN" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lemken/titan18/titan18.xml" type="attachment" category="Plow"/>
      <vehicle id="96" vehicleId="89" name="KRONE GX 520" manufacturer="KRONE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krone/gx520/gx520.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer"/>
      <vehicle id="95" vehicleId="74" name="JOHNDEERE 6R (230-250)" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/series6r/series6rextralarge.xml" type="tractor"/>
      <vehicle id="94" vehicleId="78" name="JOHNDEERE 8RX" manufacturer="JOHNDEERE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/johndeere/series8rx/series8rx.xml" type="tractor large"/>
      <vehicle id="26" vehicleId="104" colorIndex="3" name="LIZARD Pickup 2017" manufacturer="LIZARD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lizard/pickup2017/pickup2017.xml" type="car"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="16" name="Andy Hoffman" nameDe="Andreas Hoffmann" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Close Friend" role="Business Partner" job="Agricultural Machinery Dealer" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="23" bottomColorIndex="4" face="2" faceColorIndex="1" top="32" topColorIndex="1" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="6" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="2" footwearColorIndex="1" hairStyle="8" hairStyleColorIndex="4" beard="21" beardColorIndex="4">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Professional</item>
        <item>Friendly</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Andy owns an agricultural machinery dealership and is well-connected throughout the entire regional agricultural sector. His business encompasses the sale, maintenance, and repair of farm machinery, as well as the procurement of spare parts. Through his daily work, he maintains close contact with farmers, workshops, and manufacturers, giving him a precise understanding of the practical demands of modern agriculture.

In his interactions with customers and business partners, he comes across as open, friendly, and solution-oriented. He knows how to communicate on equal footing and builds trust with operations of all sizes—from small family farms to large-scale agricultural estates. His primary focus is on finding practical, real-world solutions rather than engaging in lengthy discussions about theoretical possibilities.

As a business partner, Andy is regarded as both reliable and fair. He honors his commitments, demonstrates flexibility and goodwill whenever the situation permits, and strives to resolve issues quickly and without unnecessary bureaucracy. Particularly in cases of technical breakdowns or urgent repair needs, he is often available on short notice and dedicated to minimizing downtime for his customers.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Andreas ist Inhaber eines Landmaschinenhandels und im gesamten regionalen Agrarumfeld gut vernetzt. Sein Betrieb umfasst den Verkauf, die Wartung und Reparatur von landwirtschaftlichen Maschinen sowie die Beschaffung von Ersatzteilen. Durch seine tägliche Arbeit hat er engen Kontakt zu Landwirten, Werkstätten und Herstellern und kennt die praktischen Anforderungen der Landwirtschaft sehr genau.

Im Umgang mit Kunden und Geschäftspartnern tritt er offen, freundlich und lösungsorientiert auf. Er versteht es, auf Augenhöhe zu kommunizieren und sowohl bei kleineren Betrieben als auch bei größeren Höfen Vertrauen aufzubauen. Sein Fokus liegt darauf, praxisnahe Lösungen zu finden, statt lange über theoretische Möglichkeiten zu diskutieren.

Als Geschäftspartner gilt Andreas als zuverlässig und fair. Er hält sich an Absprachen, ist kulant, wenn es die Situation erlaubt, und versucht bei Problemen schnell und unbürokratisch zu helfen. Besonders bei technischen Ausfällen oder dringenden Reparaturen ist er oft kurzfristig erreichbar und bemüht, Ausfallzeiten für seine Kunden möglichst gering zu halten.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="25" vehicleId="5" colorIndex="6" name="SKODA Kodiaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/kodiaq/kodiaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.3" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="15" name="Susan Keller" nameDe="Susanne Keller" age="31-50" gender="female" relationship="Known" role="Business Partner" job="Grain Trader" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="28" bottomColorIndex="4" face="5" faceColorIndex="1" top="53" topColorIndex="1" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="6" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="8" footwearColorIndex="3" hairStyle="13" hairStyleColorIndex="4" beard="1" beardColorIndex="4">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Neutral</item>
        <item>Suspicious</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Susan works as an independent grain trader and travels regularly throughout the region to purchase grain from local farms and subsequently resell it to regional mills and processing plants. She knows the market well, monitors prices and yields closely, and reacts swiftly to shifts in supply and demand.

In her dealings with farmers and business partners, she comes across as matter-of-fact, reserved, and unemotional. She places great emphasis on clear agreements, verifiable quality, and transparent quantity specifications. She builds trust only slowly, as she relies on facts and reliable figures within her business environment—rather than on promises or personal impressions.

Susan is highly observant and quickly spots discrepancies in offers or deliveries. As a result, some perceive her as strict or suspicious, though this is simply part of her professional prudence. She favors clear contracts and places little stock in informal arrangements or spontaneous changes.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Susanne arbeitet als unabhängige Getreidehändlerin und ist regelmäßig in der Region unterwegs, um Getreide von lokalen landwirtschaftlichen Betrieben anzukaufen und anschließend an regionale Mühlen und Verarbeitungsbetriebe weiterzuverkaufen. Sie kennt den Markt gut, beobachtet Preise und Erträge genau und reagiert schnell auf Veränderungen in Angebot und Nachfrage.

Im Umgang mit Landwirten und Geschäftspartnern wirkt sie sachlich, distanziert und wenig emotional. Sie legt großen Wert auf klare Absprachen, nachvollziehbare Qualität und transparente Mengenangaben. Vertrauen baut sie nur langsam auf, da sie sich in ihrem Geschäftsumfeld auf Fakten und verlässliche Zahlen verlässt, nicht auf Versprechen oder persönliche Eindrücke.

Susanne ist sehr aufmerksam und erkennt schnell Unstimmigkeiten in Angeboten oder Lieferungen. Dadurch wirkt sie auf manche streng oder misstrauisch, was jedoch Teil ihrer beruflichen Vorsicht ist. Sie bevorzugt klare Verträge und hält wenig von informellen Absprachen oder spontanen Änderungen.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="127" vehicleId="429" name="KRAMPE SKS 30/1050" manufacturer="KRAMPE" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/krampe/sks30_150/sks30_150.xml" type="attachment" category="Trailer Semi"/>
      <vehicle id="126" vehicleId="500" name="VOLVO FH16" manufacturer="VOLVO" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/volvo/fh16/fh16.xml" type="truck"/>
      <vehicle id="88" vehicleId="104" colorIndex="5" name="LIZARD Pickup 2017" manufacturer="LIZARD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lizard/pickup2017/pickup2017.xml" type="car"/>
      <vehicle id="24" vehicleId="91" name="KUBOTA RTV-XG850 SIDEKICK" manufacturer="KUBOTA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/kubota/rtvxg850/rtvxg850.xml" type="car"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="14" name="Martin Walker" nameDe="Martin Wagner" age="50-99" gender="male" relationship="Known" role="Official" job="Mayor" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="10" bottomColorIndex="4" face="1" faceColorIndex="1" top="23" topColorIndex="1" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="6" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="8" footwearColorIndex="3" hairStyle="13" hairStyleColorIndex="12" beard="1" beardColorIndex="12">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Professional</item>
        <item>Authoritative</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Martin has served as the community’s mayor for many years and is regarded as an experienced and influential figure within the town. He has been familiar with most of the region’s families, businesses, and developments for decades, and he places great importance on ensuring that the community projects an image of orderliness, stability, and sound organization to the outside world. He takes matters such as municipal finances, infrastructure, and the town’s public reputation particularly seriously.

In his interactions with others, Martin typically presents himself as composed, matter-of-fact, and decisive. He speaks calmly yet with authority, and he is accustomed to having his decisions command attention. He often conducts discussions diplomatically; however, he can be quite firm if rules are disregarded or if his decisions are openly challenged.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Martin ist seit vielen Jahren Bürgermeister der Gemeinde und gilt als erfahrene, einflussreiche Persönlichkeit im Ort. Er kennt die meisten Familien, Betriebe und Entwicklungen der Region seit Jahrzehnten und legt großen Wert darauf, dass die Gemeinde nach außen ordentlich, stabil und gut organisiert wirkt. Besonders Themen wie Gemeindefinanzen, Infrastruktur und das öffentliche Ansehen des Ortes nimmt er sehr ernst.

Im Umgang mit anderen tritt Martin meist kontrolliert, sachlich und bestimmt auf. Er spricht ruhig, aber mit Autorität, und ist es gewohnt, dass man seinen Entscheidungen Aufmerksamkeit schenkt. Diskussionen führt er oft diplomatisch, kann jedoch deutlich werden, wenn Regeln missachtet oder seine Entscheidungen offen infrage gestellt werden.

Er versucht, die Interessen der Gemeinde möglichst pragmatisch abzuwägen, auch wenn dabei nicht jeder zufrieden ist. Ordnung, Verlässlichkeit und ein funktionierendes Zusammenleben stehen für ihn klar im Vordergrund. Gerade bei Konflikten zwischen Bürgern, Betrieben oder Landwirten bemüht er sich um Lösungen, die langfristig Ruhe und Stabilität sichern.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="23" vehicleId="6" colorIndex="6" name="SKODA Enyaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/enyaq/enyaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.2" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="13" name="Lukas Brenner" nameDe="Lukas Brenner" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Friend" role="Neighbour" job="Forester" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="9" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="0" bottomColorIndex="5" face="5" faceColorIndex="1" top="0" topColorIndex="10" gloves="3" glovesColorIndex="6" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="2" footwearColorIndex="3" hairStyle="4" hairStyleColorIndex="12" beard="48" beardColorIndex="12">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Cautious</item>
        <item>Professional</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Lukas works as a forester and is responsible for the care and management of the surrounding forest areas. His duties include, among other things, inspecting reforestation efforts, maintaining forest paths, monitoring nature conservation measures, and organizing and verifying hunting permits. He knows the region's forests intimately and spends a large portion of his daily life outdoors in nature.

Despite his rather reserved nature, he is regarded as a reliable and fair-minded individual. He is always happy to share his knowledge with friends, particularly when it comes to forestry work, timber, hunting, or nature conservation. He values honest and straightforward people and gets along well with those who act responsibly and keep their word.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Lukas arbeitet als Förster und ist für die Betreuung und Verwaltung der umliegenden Waldgebiete zuständig. Zu seinen Aufgaben gehören unter anderem die Kontrolle von Aufforstungen, die Pflege von Waldwegen, die Überwachung von Naturschutzmaßnahmen sowie die Organisation und Prüfung von Jagdgenehmigungen. Er kennt die Wälder der Region sehr genau und verbringt einen Großteil seines Alltags draußen in der Natur.

Trotz seiner eher zurückhaltenden Art gilt er als verlässlicher und fairer Mensch. Freunden hilft er gerne mit seinem Wissen weiter, besonders wenn es um Waldarbeit, Holz, Jagd oder Naturschutz geht. Er schätzt ehrliche und direkte Menschen und kommt mit Personen gut aus, die verantwortungsvoll handeln und ihr Wort halten.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="22" vehicleId="104" colorIndex="29" name="LIZARD Pickup 2017" manufacturer="LIZARD" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/lizard/pickup2017/pickup2017.xml" type="car"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="11" name="Kyle Bennett" nameDe="Kyle Brandt" age="31-50" gender="male" relationship="Close Friend" role="Civilian" hathair="0" glasses="5" glassesColorIndex="0" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="0" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="0" bottom="9" bottomColorIndex="0" face="2" faceColorIndex="0" top="35" topColorIndex="0" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="0" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="0" footwear="16" footwearColorIndex="0" hairStyle="4" hairStyleColorIndex="0" beard="0" beardColorIndex="0">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Neutral</item>
        <item>Friendly</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Kyle works as a personal trainer and spends a large part of his daily life in the gym or engaged in athletic activities. Physical fitness, discipline, and a healthy lifestyle are important to him—without him ever coming across as preachy. He enjoys motivating others and usually manages to quickly win people over with his open and laid-back demeanor.

As a good friend of Joe, he is reliable and helpful—especially when someone needs practical support or motivation. He tends to focus on lifting people up and offering distractions rather than dwelling at length on difficulties. He generally avoids conflict, preferring instead to keep the atmosphere light.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Kyle arbeitet als Personal Trainer und verbringt einen großen Teil seines Alltags im Fitnessstudio oder mit sportlichen Aktivitäten. Körperliche Fitness, Disziplin und ein gesunder Lebensstil sind ihm wichtig, ohne dass er dabei belehrend wirkt. Er motiviert andere gerne und schafft es meist, Menschen mit seiner offenen und lockeren Art schnell für sich zu gewinnen.

Als guter Freund von Joe ist er zuverlässig und hilfsbereit, besonders wenn jemand praktische Unterstützung oder Motivation braucht. Er versucht eher, Menschen aufzubauen und abzulenken, anstatt lange über Schwierigkeiten zu reden. Konflikte meidet er meistens und versucht lieber, die Stimmung locker zu halten.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="20" vehicleId="67" colorIndex="7" name="INTERNATIONAL Series 200" manufacturer="INTERNATIONAL" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/international/series200/series200.xml" type="car"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="10" name="Sharon Whitaker" nameDe="Sharon Weidmann" age="50-99" gender="female" relationship="Strained" role="Official" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="4" bottomColorIndex="4" face="3" faceColorIndex="1" top="20" topColorIndex="3" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="1" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="8" footwearColorIndex="2" hairStyle="16" hairStyleColorIndex="6" beard="0" beardColorIndex="1">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Authoritative</item>
        <item>Cautious</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Sharon works in the municipal administration, where she ensures clear procedures and harmonious community living. For farmers, this often involves matters such as nighttime quiet, cleanliness, and nuisances related to odors or noise. Outside of work, she generally tries to distance herself from constant organizing and oversight; she declines to engage in such discussions during her off-hours.

She is regarded as quiet, matter-of-fact, and rather reserved, though she can be friendly and humorous once she gets to know someone better. She typically approaches discussions in a sober and direct manner. In her free time, she enjoys reading, going for walks, or spending time in her garden. She tends to avoid large crowds and bustling environments. Order and reliability are important to her, both professionally and privately. Nevertheless, she makes a conscious effort to be more relaxed after work hours and to avoid constantly bringing her work home with her.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Sharon arbeitet in der Gemeindeverwaltung und achtet auf klare Abläufe und ein ordentliches Zusammenleben. Das Betrifft bei Landwirten oft die Nachtruhe, Verschmutzungen und Geruchs- oder Lärmbelästigungen. Außerhalb der Arbeit versucht sie meist, Abstand vom ständigen Organisieren und Kontrollieren zu bekommen. Gespräche der Form lehnt sie dort ab.

Sie gilt als ruhig, sachlich und eher zurückhaltend, kann aber freundlich und humorvoll sein, wenn sie jemanden besser kennt. Diskussionen geht sie meist nüchtern und direkt an. In ihrer Freizeit liest sie gerne, geht spazieren oder verbringt Zeit im Garten. Größere Menschenmengen und viel Trubel meidet sie eher. Ordnung und Verlässlichkeit sind ihr wichtig, auch privat. Trotzdem versucht sie bewusst, nach Feierabend lockerer zu sein und Arbeit nicht ständig mit nach Hause zu nehmen.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="19" vehicleId="5" colorIndex="4" name="SKODA Kodiaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/kodiaq/kodiaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.3" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="2" name="John Carter" nameDe="John Huber" age="21-30" gender="male" relationship="Family" role="Family Member" job="Farmer" belongsToFarm="true" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="1" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="1" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="1" bottom="11" bottomColorIndex="4" face="1" faceColorIndex="1" top="7" topColorIndex="18" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="1" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="12" footwear="2" footwearColorIndex="1" hairStyle="14" hairStyleColorIndex="20" beard="0" beardColorIndex="20">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Stressed</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>John Huber is the brother of Joe Carter —the player character—and grew up alongside him on the family farm. From an early age, farming was a natural and integral part of his life; consequently, he continues to strive to contribute to the daily farm routine as much as his abilities allow. However, due to a medical condition that has physically limited him for several years, he is now able to undertake only lighter and simpler tasks. This weighs on him more heavily than he openly reveals.

In the past, John was significantly more active in the fields and involved in physically demanding labor. Today, he struggles to come to terms with the fact that many things no longer function as they once did. He feels particularly useless—or like a burden to his family—when others have to take on the heavy work, even though no one intentionally makes him feel this way.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>John Huber ist der Bruder von Joe  Huber (Spieler) und gemeinsam mit ihm auf dem Familienhof aufgewachsen. Die Landwirtschaft war für ihn schon früh ein selbstverständlicher Teil des Lebens, weshalb er bis heute versucht, so gut wie möglich am Hofalltag mitzuwirken. Durch eine Erkrankung, die ihn seit einigen Jahren körperlich einschränkt, kann er jedoch nur noch leichtere und einfachere Arbeiten übernehmen. Das belastet ihn mehr, als er offen zeigt.

Früher war John deutlich aktiver auf dem Feld und bei körperlich anstrengenden Tätigkeiten dabei. Heute fällt es ihm schwer, akzeptieren zu müssen, dass vieles nicht mehr so funktioniert wie früher. Besonders wenn andere die schwere Arbeit übernehmen müssen, fühlt er sich schnell nutzlos oder als Belastung für die Familie, obwohl ihm niemand dieses Gefühl bewusst vermittelt.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="10" vehicleId="5" colorIndex="2" name="SKODA Kodiaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/kodiaq/kodiaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.3" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
    <neighbour id="1" name="Mary Carter" nameDe="Maria Huber" age="31-50" gender="female" relationship="Family" role="Family Member" job="Farmer" belongsToFarm="true" hathair="0" glasses="0" glassesColorIndex="0" facegear="0" facegearColorIndex="0" onepiece="0" onepieceColorIndex="0" bottom="17" bottomColorIndex="1" face="1" faceColorIndex="0" top="15" topColorIndex="1" gloves="0" glovesColorIndex="0" headgear="0" headgearColorIndex="0" footwear="7" footwearColorIndex="0" hairStyle="16" hairStyleColorIndex="4" beard="6" beardColorIndex="0">
      <behaviour>
        <item>Friendly</item>
        <item>Professional</item>
        <item>Supportive</item>
      </behaviour>
      <roleScenarioDescription>Mary Carter is the wife of Joe Huber (the Player) and is deeply integrated into both family life and the daily routine of the farm. Although she is not a formally trained farmer, she regularly pitches in with farm chores—whether in the barn or out in the fields—whenever a helping hand is needed. Particularly during busy periods, she steps in as a matter of course, striving to support her husband and family by taking care of things behind the scenes.

She is regarded as a quiet, warm-hearted, and dependable individual who typically approaches conflicts in a calm, objective, and patient manner. She is open and helpful toward others, though she also expects honesty and mutual respect in return. To strangers, she may initially appear somewhat reserved, but she quickly warms up once approached with friendliness.

In her daily life, she often handles organizational matters concerning the household, the family, and the farm. She makes a point of ensuring that, despite the heavy workload, a sense of family cohesion and a pleasant atmosphere are maintained. She generally attempts to navigate stressful situations with composure and pragmatic solutions, even if she occasionally takes on too much responsibility herself.</roleScenarioDescription>
      <roleScenarioDescriptionDe>Maria Huber ist die Frau von Joe Huber (Spieler) und fest in das Familienleben sowie den Alltag am Hof eingebunden. Obwohl sie keine ausgebildete Landwirtin ist, hilft sie regelmäßig auf dem Hof, im Stall oder bei der Feldarbeit mit, wenn Unterstützung gebraucht wird. Besonders in arbeitsreichen Zeiten springt sie selbstverständlich ein und versucht, ihrem Mann und der Familie den Rücken freizuhalten.

Sie gilt als ruhige, herzliche und verlässliche Person, die Konflikte meist sachlich und mit Geduld angeht. Gegenüber anderen Menschen verhält sie sich offen und hilfsbereit, erwartet aber auch Ehrlichkeit und gegenseitigen Respekt. Auf Fremde wirkt sie zunächst eher zurückhaltend, taut aber schnell auf, wenn man ihr freundlich begegnet.

Im Alltag kümmert sie sich oft um organisatorische Dinge rund um Haushalt, Familie und Hof. Sie achtet darauf, dass trotz der vielen Arbeit ein gewisser Zusammenhalt und eine angenehme Atmosphäre erhalten bleiben. Stressige Situationen versucht sie meist mit Ruhe und pragmatischen Lösungen zu bewältigen, auch wenn sie sich manchmal zu viel Verantwortung auflädt.</roleScenarioDescriptionDe>
      <vehicle id="9" vehicleId="6" colorIndex="5" name="SKODA Enyaq" manufacturer="SKODA" xmlFilename="data/vehicles/skoda/enyaq/enyaq.xml" type="car" npcOffsetX="1.2" npcOffsetY="0" npcOffsetZ="0" npcOffsetRotation="0"/>
    </neighbour>
  </neighbours>
</scenario>
